<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>MidnightSlicer Blog</title>
	<link href="https://mnsr.win
https://github.com/MidnightSlicer/atom.xml" rel="self" />
	<updated>2023-10-07T22:46:52Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>Dylan H</name>
	</author>
	<id>https://mnsr.win
https://github.com/MidnightSlicer,2023-09-19:default-atom-feed/</id>
	<entry>
		<title>Hello World!</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Hello World!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2023-09-27&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my blog! I have always wanted to have a blog of my own, and that desire was spurred on by my decision to leave social media. I love writing and I needed a place to express that love that was mine. When I became aware of open source, freedom, privacy, and all that other cool stuff I wanted to not only use a platform free of spyware, but I also wanted to &lt;em&gt;own the platform&lt;/em&gt;. I have already expressed that by running my own Minecraft server, Matrix server, and a few other servers for my friends and I, so to me a website is kinda the logical next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So please, enjoy your stay, enjoy the reading, and enjoy the learning!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://mnsr.win
https://github.com/MidnightSlicer/hello-world"/>
		<id>https://mnsr.win
https://github.com/MidnightSlicer/hello-world</id>
		<updated>2023-09-27T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2023-09-27T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>My Experience with Computers</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;My Experience with Computers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2023-09-30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I am just getting started on this blog thing, I should talk about a little bit of history of me and computers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Windows XP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first time using a computer for real was on an old Windows XP workstation that was &lt;em&gt;liberated&lt;/em&gt; from a dumpster. It was (and still is, it is on my project shelf to become a pfSense router) an amazing little computer for what I did. I think I was about 7, and I only managed to break it a few times. I was trying so hard to find a way to edit videos on it to make Lego stop motions. The problem is there were not any free ones that were also low powered enough to run on that thing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The iMac&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When my parents saw my interest they surprised me and my siblings with an iMac. Granted, they also had work that required a powerful computer, but hey, I got my own account and was free to use it when not doing school or someone else was using it. From there, I used iMovie to create some really epic Lego stop motions. As I got older I started exploring things I may want to do... How I wanted to spend the rest of my life. That is when I decided to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@blenderguru&quot;&gt;learn&lt;/a&gt; 3D modeling in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blender.org/&quot;&gt;Blender&lt;/a&gt;. When I started to push the limits of the now aging iMac, I got my first job and decided it was time to buy my own computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Alienware R15&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can I start by saying don&#39;t buy an Alienware? There is just better ways to spend money. Anyway, I bought an Alienware R15 with a 8th gen Intel i7 and an Nvidia RTX 2060. At this point the main difference between macOS and Windows 10 was the &quot;X&quot; button moving, I was not that technical yet. The Alienware Laptop served me well as I worked on my 3D modeling skills. While 3D modeling, I discovered scripting with Python. I started to really enjoy making little Python scripts more than 3D modeling. After about a year of trying other things for short periods of time, I knew what I was made for. I am a software developer. I am naturally inclined to think like a computer and a touch of OCD helps me keep my code clean. After about 3 years with the Alienware, I had discovered Linux and I wanted to try it out. After raise at my job, the discovery of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@linustechtips&quot;&gt;LTT&lt;/a&gt;, and more general computing knowledge, it was time. I finally saved up and built my first desktop computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My First Build, &lt;em&gt;MidnightSlicer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first build went very well. I didn&#39;t have to take it apart again to get it to work like some do and it was overall an amazing experience (other than the whole MSI thing but I will write about that later). I built near the end of the crypto boom so I was only able to afford an RX 6600 XT, but it has been enough for what I do. The majority of my time on computers is spent doing CPU heavy work, with gaming being about a third priority. One interesting thing about this computer is I went out of my way to avoid RGB lights... Hence the name, MidnightSlicer. I installed Windows 11 on it for a little bit, but when I was finally ready to switch to Linux I installed Manjaro and have not went back to Windows since. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://mnsr.win
https://github.com/MidnightSlicer/computers-and-me"/>
		<id>https://mnsr.win
https://github.com/MidnightSlicer/computers-and-me</id>
		<updated>2023-09-30T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2023-09-30T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>Joining The 512KB Club</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Joining The 512KB Club&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2023-10-07&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a bit of a nerd for optimization. It is always satisfying to me when I am able to shave a fifth of a second off some operation or trivial task. I am the physical embodiment of spending 5 hours to save time on a 5 minute task. It is just so rewarding to me, even if some people don&#39;t get it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The 512KB Club?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;https://512kb.club/&quot;&gt;512KB Club&lt;/a&gt; is sort of like a webring for websites that are less than 512KB... obviously. On their home page they point out that many websites are now &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;several MB in size&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and bloated with JavaScript. There is almost no reason for a website to be that large. So, I decided to check mine... and it fits! My home page is about 15KB. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why Does This Matter?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, from a completely practical standpoint, smaller webpages result in faster loading times. If a webpage is large, people on poor internet connections or slower devices will struggle to load the page. In most cases, if a page takes too long to load people will just leave, which is sad if you want them to read your stuff. 
Even if you have a good internet connection and a simi-modern device, you will still see a notable hitch when loading large webpages. Just go to some bloated site, open the dev tools, go to the network section, and refresh the page to watch all those assets load in. It is wild. 
I think the main reason for smaller webpages is &lt;em&gt;there is no good reason for them to be large&lt;/em&gt;. It is just a waste to create pretty visuals. I am constantly reminded of this when I have to visit a utility company&#39;s website. It is just stupid. They&#39;ve got fire, water, and lighting effects as a scroll down the page just trying to find the little &quot;pay my bills&quot; button. I don&#39;t want to see how much money you wasted on web design. I want to pay my bills and immediately leave. I guess the utility companies in my area got some government grant and they had to spend it somehow, so they made a &quot;pretty&quot; website. Beauty is in the eye of the beholder, and I behold JavaScript bloat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always bring it back to privacy. But really, if your website is smaller, it is harder to cram trackers in. It is certainly possible, but it is harder. It is also easier to review your website&#39;s code if there is less of it. I obviously believe you should have the freedom to visit a website without leaving a stain of your existence with details about your browser and browsing history (I&#39;m looking at you &lt;a href=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;https://brave.com/web-standards-at-brave/7-googles-topics-api/&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;). I know Nginx logs some information about the visitors of my website, but there are a few reasons that doesn&#39;t matter as much:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am not selling ads based off that information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am not selling that information to someone who would sell ads based off that information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;m not creepy 👁️&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I like small websites because they are more efficient. What am I going to do about these recent discoveries? obviously I am going to submit to join the 512KB Club! I will update this page if I get added.  &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://mnsr.win
https://github.com/MidnightSlicer/512KB"/>
		<id>https://mnsr.win
https://github.com/MidnightSlicer/512KB</id>
		<updated>2023-10-07T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2023-10-07T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
</feed>
