<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Dylan's Blog</title>
	<link href="https://mnsr.win/atom.xml" rel="self" />
	<updated>2024-01-15T17:10:45Z</updated>
	<author>
		<name>Dylan</name>
	</author>
	<id>https://mnsr.win,2023-09-19:default-atom-feed/</id>
	<entry>
		<title>Spooky Software</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Spooky Software&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2023-10-21&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it is October, the month that some people celebrate &quot;Halloween&quot; and dress up spooky. While I do not really like the those celebrations and don&#39;t participate I will use the &quot;Spooky Month&quot; excuse to talk about spooky software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is &quot;Spooky Software&quot;?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spooky Software is any application, service, or other software that does not respect the user&#39;s privacy. Most spooky software is proprietary, but there is open source spooky software. Some examples of spooky software would be: Google Chrome, TikTok, YouTube, Discord, etc. These apps are not only proprietary, but proven to spy on their users. That is spooky! 👻 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Do I Do About Spooky Software?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are reading this, I likely don&#39;t need to explain why you should not want to be spied on. If you are still ok with being spied on, this post will not address that belief specifically. I do want to understand that thought process, so I am researching it and I will write about it when I finish. Anyway, the best answer is to &lt;em&gt;stop using it&lt;/em&gt;, however, that is not always possible. There are two options to handle your spooky software:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find an alternative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leverage tools to stay safe while still using the spooky software&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The former is generally easier and the most recommended way, however, sometimes you just have to use the spooky software for work or for a given hobby. I don&#39;t think you should quit work or give up a hobby in the name of privacy in most cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Finding an Alternative&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I have liked about switching to Linux is learning there are other ways to do what I need to do on computers. Used to, I thought Microsoft Word was the only way to do my school. Partly because I had never used anything else, and partly because they said to use it. While I understand that there are &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; people who cannot switch to an operating system that respects their privacy, almost everyone can find privacy respecting alternatives to some of the software they use. A really good resource for this is &lt;a href=&quot;https://alternativeto.net/&quot;&gt;AlternativeTo&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AlternativeTo has a search bar that lets you search for almost any tool you can think of, and they list other tools that do the same or similar thing. For example, searching &quot;Microsoft Word&quot; returns LibreOffice Writer, Apache OpenOffice Writer, Google Docs, etc. They have tags that indicate weather the software is open source or proprietary, free or payed, and what operating systems it supports. There are also user reviews where there is discussion about ease of use or software stability. Most of the time you can use privacy friendly alternatives without leaving your current operating system or changing your current workflow. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Protecting Yourself From Spooky Software&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you just can&#39;t stop using spooky software. I don&#39;t need to give examples of this because if you are in this unfortunate situation you know how it feels. For me personally, I can&#39;t uninstall Google services from my mobile phone because my school forces me to have Duo for two factor authentication (even though it is an objectively worse way to do 2FA then rolling codes). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to protect yourself from spooky software is sandboxing. Sandboxing is forcing the software to run in an environment that keeps it separate from the rest of your system. When software is sandboxed, it can&#39;t access other processes, data, or sensors unless it is explicitly allowed. On GrapheneOS, Google Play apps are sandboxed by default, making it difficult for them to do system-wide spying. On Linux, you can use simply use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flatpak.org/&quot;&gt;Flatpak&lt;/a&gt; version of a given software. &lt;a href=&quot;https://flathub.org/apps/com.github.tchx84.Flatseal&quot;&gt;Flatseal&lt;/a&gt; is an application that lets you have very fine control over each of your Flatpak apps. Flatpaks run in a sandbox by default, and some app developers only support Flatpaks as it makes their workflow easier. If you are using an unoffical Flatpak packaging, make sure you trust the person doing the packaging. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Bing AI first came out I wanted to use it, but it was only available in Microsoft Edge. Since I didn&#39;t want to use Edge on my PC (because it is a privacy nightmare) I used the Flatpak version. Using Flatseal, I was able to lock down the permissions it had so I could use it without too much tracking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other things you can do is running applications in a VM, which gives your a lot of protection since malware to escape hypervisors is very expensive and sought after. One good way to do this system-wide is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qubes-os.org/&quot;&gt;QubesOS&lt;/a&gt;. I have personally never used it, but I really want to and plan to review it at some point. QubesOS has the endorsement of Edward Snowden, Let&#39;s Encrypt, and many dark web users, which is good enough for me to call it good. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in conclusion, there is actually a lot you can do to be more private online. If you are feeling trapped or just getting started on privacy, I hope this guide can point you in the right direction. There are also some good things you can do to remain slightly more anonymous online like using a VPN, but this should be done with caution and only when you fully understand how VPNs work. I personally recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://mullvad.net/&quot;&gt;Mullvad VPN&lt;/a&gt;, but you should still research them on your own. Remember, privacy is not a destination, it is a journey. I encourage anyone to just start where they are and take small steps! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still getting started on this website, but I want to have a lot of resources for people who are interested in privacy and security. I am making some really cool resources I can&#39;t wait to share, so subscribe to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://mnsr.win/atom.xml&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; feed and stay tuned! &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://mnsr.win/spooky-month"/>
		<id>https://mnsr.win/spooky-month</id>
		<updated>2023-10-21T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2023-10-21T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>Cybersecurity is Important -- Password Managers can Help</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Cybersecurity is Important -- Password Managers can Help&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2024-01-15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you just want to know how to set up a password manager, go read my post &lt;a href=&quot;https://mnsr.win/password-manager-setup/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity is a very popular topic these days. With companies making the news almost every week having some sort of data leak or cyber attack, it is a subject one should rightfully be concerned about. Unfortunately, most are not as concerned or as aware as I think they should be. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is difficult to find information about cybersecurity. Almost every post on it on the internet is made by a company that is trying to sell you something. While there can be (and often is) good information in these posts, you know the information is being presented to you to get your money, not keep you safe. Again, this is not even a bad thing, but I believe it still has an effect on the reader. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, before we go any further, let me tell you about our sponsor, NordVP- (just kidding &lt;s&gt;Proton please sponsor me&lt;/s&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It isn&#39;t hard (Seriously)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two things you can do to bolster your online security:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a unique, random password for each website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Two-Factor Authentication (2FA) everywhere possible (especially social media, email, and banking accounts)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue with the former is human brains are not meant to randomly generate and remember tens of passwords. Since memorization is impractical, we do the predictable thing... use one password for everything. Even if that one password is a &quot;good password&quot;, it is still everywhere. If any service who has that password just so happens to be storing it in plain text gets hacked, guess what? That password is now in hacker databases likely tied to your email. It is only a matter of time before someone starts trying your user info on other services and gets into one of your accounts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that password managers are just a necessary evil. Password managers act as the one secure place you store all of your passwords. Instead of writing them down on a piece of paper under your keyboard, or worse, put them in some cloud synced notes application, the password manager stores all of your passwords safely in one place and gives you easy access to them. The achilles&#39; heel in this whole plan is your &quot;Master password&quot;, the single password that protects your vault. Below, I will discuss a few password manager options, and then I will send you to my next post to show you how to set up a password manager. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bad Password Managers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of a password manager scares those who know enough about security to know not to share their passwords, I mean, think about it. &quot;Hey can you put all of your passwords in a spreadsheet and upload it to our servers?&quot;, that is essentially what you are doing with a password manager (unless you are using &lt;a href=&quot;https://keepassxc.org&quot;&gt;KeePassXC&lt;/a&gt;). BUT! There are password managers you can trust, it is just important to use one of them... instead of a creepy one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few I would never even consider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LastPass 🤮&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything built-in to any browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;McAfee Password Manger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything that isn&#39;t open source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Good Password Managers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good password manger is the one that offers the features you want, without compromising on security. The password managers mentioned above are ones that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnet.com/tech/services-and-software/still-using-lastpass-you-need-to-do-these-5-things/&quot;&gt;have massive data breaches&lt;/a&gt;, are unencrypted, ran by a company I wouldn&#39;t trust with anything, or just general bad practice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two password managers I have extensive experience with and would recommend to anyone who doesn&#39;t have one. Also, let me just say that picking a password manager (if it is a good one) is not a permanent decision. Most password managers allow you to export your passwords just like the allow you to import them, meaning once you have your passwords in a way that one password manager can read them, most others will be able to read them too. Password manager hopping is actually super easy, and takes me about 3 minutes once the password manager itself is setup. So, without further adieu, my favorite password managers: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitwarden.com/&quot;&gt;Bitwarden&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://proton.me/pass&quot;&gt;Proton Pass&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bitwarden: the affordable, simple option&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bitwarden.com/&quot;&gt;Bitwarden&lt;/a&gt; is probably the number one password manager that comes to mind when you say you strictly want an open source password manager. They have been around for a while and have always been know for transparency and security. Bitwarden also has a free plan that offers all of the major features one would expect from a password manager. Bitwarden is also active in the login security community, participating in efforts to make passkeys more common and useful for users. If you decide to pay for Bitwarden, which I recommend after using it for a few weeks to make sure you like it, the subscription is $10 (USD) per year (or $40 per year for 6 users). The subscription gives you access to the Bitwarden Authenticator, Bitwarden&#39;s 2FA manager built directly into your password manager. And a few more nice to have features, like secure file uploads, security reports, and emergency access. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Proton Pass: the powerful, integrated option&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to &lt;a href=&quot;https://iv.ggtyler.dev/watch?v=WTWyosdkx44&quot;&gt;doot&lt;/a&gt; Proton&#39;s horn, but I will start by saying that Proton Pass just looks plain better than Bitwarden. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proton Pass browser extension locked
&lt;img style=&quot;border:0;margin-top:2rem;&quot; src=&quot;../public/posts/password-managers/protonpass-locked.png&quot; alt=&quot;Proton Pass browser extension locked&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitwarden browser extension locked
&lt;img style=&quot;border:0;margin-top:2rem;&quot; src=&quot;../public/posts/password-managers/bitwarden-locked.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bitwarden browser extension locked&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://proton.me/pass&quot;&gt;Proton Pass&lt;/a&gt; is a newer entry to the password manager space. It is made by the same team who made Proton Mail, the encrypted and secure email service that doesn&#39;t spy on you. Just because it is new doesn&#39;t make it worse. I have used each extensively in both Chrome (Brave) and Firefox as well as their Android apps and I think that Proton Pass&#39;s auto fill just works better in all cases. The free Proton Pass plan allows you to store 2FA keys, which I think is important, and also gives you access to 10 &quot;&lt;em&gt;hide-my-email&lt;/em&gt; aliases&quot;. Email aliases are a unique approach that Proton has engineered and I haven&#39;t seen anything quite like it. Basically, using their tooling from &lt;a href=&quot;https://simplelogin.io/&quot;&gt;SimpleLogin&lt;/a&gt;, Proton Pass can generate an email address for you to give websites when signing up. This alias points to Proton&#39;s servers and when an email is sent to that address, it immediately gets redirected to your inbox. When that company inevitably either sells/leaks your email address and it starts getting spammed with ads, you can just go to your dashboard and disable (or delete) the address. Boom. No more email spam. It is just gone. Unfortunately, if you are only looking for a password manager, Proton Pass may not be for you. Proton Pass works best (and is a better deal) if it is bought in a Proton Mail bundle, which includes Mail, Calendar, Drive, VPN and Pass. However, as a Proton Family Plan user myself, I highly recommend looking into protecting yourself and those you love with Proton. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What about KeePass/KeePassXC?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KeePass (and its fork, KeePassXC) is a great password manager that I really love a lot. It takes a little different approach to managing passwords than pretty much any other password manager. KeePass is an &lt;em&gt;offline&lt;/em&gt; password manager. KeePass doesn&#39;t have some server somewhere that you put your passwords in. Instead, it is up to you to manage the password database. This gives you maximum control over your data, and you can even make your own KeePass server to get a similar experience to using the cloud. However, it is a lot more technical than one of the other plug-and-play password managers. You are also &lt;em&gt;very responsible&lt;/em&gt; for your passwords. If you loose your database... your done. Gone. Just plain out of luck. There is nothing anyone anywhere can do about that. With online password managers, you can set recovery methods to get into your account in case you misplace your password. If a natural disaster hits your house, the cloud password managers will be unaffected and you will still have all of your logins. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of me wants to rent a Virtual Private Server (VPS) and run my own KeePass server, but man, Proton Pass (my current password manager) is so nice and easy to use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What about 1Password?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a more technical topic, but in short I do not recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://1password.community/discussion/comment/114870/#Comment_114870&quot;&gt;1Password since they are not interested in open sourcing their client applications&lt;/a&gt;. While their intentions seem sincere, my personal biases lead me to be more skeptical when you won&#39;t trust me to read the code that is running on my computer. Trust in IT is bad. Never trust developers and companies. The password managers I mentioned above allow the user to review the software, reducing trust placed in the developers of the project. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So! Now you know a lot about password managers, why they are important, and which ones you can look into. Now, if you are ready to dive in and set up your password manager, then just click this &lt;a href=&quot;https://mnsr.win/password-manager-setup&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; to follow my guide on setting up Bitwarden. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://mnsr.win/password-managers"/>
		<id>https://mnsr.win/password-managers</id>
		<updated>2024-01-15T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2024-01-15T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>How to setup a Password Manager</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;How to setup a Password Manager&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2024-01-15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to know more about password managers, read my post about them &lt;a href=&quot;https://mnsr.win/password-managers&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, I am going to show you how to set up Bitwarden as your password manager. This guide can be applied to any desktop browser and pretty much any password manager. Your screen will likely look different than mine, but the principle will be similar. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this guide I will be using Brave on desktop, which looks very similar to Google Chrome and Microsoft Edge. If you are on Firefox or &lt;a href=&quot;https://mnsr.win/safari&quot;&gt;Safari&lt;/a&gt; the steps are pretty much the same as well. I highly recommend doing this on a desktop computer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#create-a-bitwarden-account&quot;&gt;Create a Bitwarden account&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#import-your-passwords-into-bitwarden&quot;&gt;Import your passwords into Bitwarden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#install-the-browser-addonextension&quot;&gt;Install the browser addon/extension&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install the mobile app (&lt;a href=&quot;#install-the-mobile-app-android&quot;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;) (&lt;a href=&quot;#install-the-mobile-app-ios&quot;&gt;iOS&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#moving-forward&quot;&gt;Moving forward&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Create a Bitwarden Account&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first step to using Bitwarden. This will be the hardest step in this guide. Everything after this is super simple. Go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitwarden.com/&quot;&gt;bitwarden.com&lt;/a&gt; and hit &quot;Get started&quot; in the top right of the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should redirect you to vault.bitwarden.com. Here, you can enter your email, name, master password, and a master password hint. The email and name are easy, but the master password part can be hard. The master password should be something long (at least 12 characters). Depending on how you like to do things, it also needs to be something you can remember. Personally, I used a &lt;a href=&quot;https://randomwordgenerator.com/&quot;&gt;random word generator&lt;/a&gt; set to 5 words, added dashes and numbers, wrote it down on my paper, and called it a day. This is an example of what I would make using a random word generator:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mean3-Different1-Conclusion8-Original4-Ostracize6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, this is the only password I write down on paper, then I put that paper in a safe place where my loved ones can find it if something were to happen to me. This gives them easy access to all of my logins and makes dealing with business much easier (trust me, I have dealt with relatives passing and leaving no clues on how to get into their stuff). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you are ready, check the agree to terms box and then click &quot;Create account&quot;. Prove you are a human (if you are one) or hire someone on fiver to do it for you (if you are ChatGPT). Do not save the password to your browser, that is what we are trying to get rid of, remember? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will prompt you to enter your email once more, and then enter your password again. Then, you will finally be in your new Bitwarden account. Congrats! You are basically done! Verify your email and continue to the next step. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Import your Passwords into Bitwarden&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it is time for the fun part! You can import all the passwords you have saved in your browser to Bitwarden with minimal effort. Once logged in and email verified, go to Tools -&amp;gt; Import data. You can leave the Import destination on &quot;My vault&quot; and leave the folder box alone. These are for sorting your vaults later, something I won&#39;t get into here. Select a file format. There are several to choose from, but since you are using a browser, you just need to select the browser you are using. Note that if you are using Brave, Edge or any other Chrome based browser, select &quot;Chrome (csv)&quot;. When you select a file format, Bitwarden will give you a link to a tutorial on how to import the passwords. Just follow that. (Note you can also put &quot;chrome://password-manager/settings&quot; into your Chrome based browser and be redirected to it&#39;s password settings). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you upload the file, you can just click &quot;Import data&quot; and batta-bing-batta-boom. You are off to the races. You can now install the browser extension, mobile apps, or desktop app to handle all of your auto fill. You can also repeat the import instruction on other browsers you have (like maybe a separate browser on your phone) and add those to your vault. If you end up importing duplicates, don&#39;t worry. You can always come back to &lt;a href=&quot;https://vault.bitwarden.com/&quot;&gt;vault.bitwarden.com&lt;/a&gt; and easily manage your passwords. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Install the Browser Addon/Extension&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming soon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Install the Mobile App (Android)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming soon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Install the Mobile App (iOS)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming soon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Moving Forward&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, all you have to do is go into all of your devices and tell them to stop autofilling your stuff. Bitwarden handles that now. When you create new accounts you can save them to Bitwarden and use it&#39;s password generator to randomly generate passwords for every account. You can also slowly go back and change all your passwords on your existing accounts using randomly generated ones. I would also recommend adding some sort of 2-Factor Authentication (2FA) to your Bitwarden account. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking this small step for password security will really help reduce the likelihood of you being hacked in the future. It also makes it easier for your family to handle important business if something does happen to you and you are unable to assist. Overall, password managers may have some downsides, but the benefits outweigh the downsides every why I measure it. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://mnsr.win/password-manager-setup"/>
		<id>https://mnsr.win/password-manager-setup</id>
		<updated>2024-01-15T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2024-01-15T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>Hello World!</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Hello World!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2023-09-27&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my blog! I have always wanted to have a blog of my own, and that desire was spurred on by my decision to leave social media. I love writing and I needed a place to express that love that was mine. When I became aware of open source, freedom, privacy, and all that other cool stuff I wanted to not only use a platform free of spyware, but I also wanted to &lt;em&gt;own the platform&lt;/em&gt;. I have already expressed that by running my own Minecraft server, Matrix server, and a few other servers for my friends and I, so to me a website is kinda the logical next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So please, enjoy your stay, enjoy the reading, and enjoy the learning!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://mnsr.win/hello-world"/>
		<id>https://mnsr.win/hello-world</id>
		<updated>2023-09-27T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2023-09-27T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>The Darktheme Club</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;The Darktheme Club&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2023-10-14&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, I talked about &lt;a href=&quot;https://mnsr.win/512KB/&quot;&gt;joining the 512kb club&lt;/a&gt; and I mostly spoke on the attractiveness and art of making a small (in size, not in value) website. I argued that a better web is one where the user is not required to download several megabytes of bloated JS frameworks and spyware (which is a type of malware). Today, I am writing about joining the &lt;a href=&quot;https://darktheme.club&quot;&gt;Darktheme Club&lt;/a&gt;. This is less of a principle and more of a personal preference, but if you know me you know I love dark mode. Everything must be dark mode for me. If an application doesn&#39;t have dark mode I will consider uninstalling it. I just don&#39;t like having my eyes burned when I just want to read something. I also just think it looks slick. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Darktheme Club is simply a club of websites that have dark mode in some way, shape, or form. Some are dark only (like mine!), some are based off your operating system, and some are picked by the user. This is less about saying &quot;You must use dark mode&quot; and more about pointing out the importance of using tools like this to share your personal site with like minded people. I highly recommend running your own blog/site (or &lt;a href=&quot;https://bt.ht/dump/&quot;&gt;brain dump&lt;/a&gt;, more accurately). But, without algorithms to share our stuff and manipulate us, the web really starts to look like a lonely place. A lot of these little personal sites will not appear on an internet search, leaving it up to the community to share its own content. Webrings and clubs are excellent ways to do this. Start your own site and join some clubs! It is really fun and you may find some cool sites along the way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I find more clubs and webrings I will join them and add their links where it is needed. For me, all of them are on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://mnsr.win/about/&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt; page unless one says it must be on the footer, for example. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://mnsr.win/darkmode"/>
		<id>https://mnsr.win/darkmode</id>
		<updated>2023-10-14T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2023-10-14T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>My Experience with Computers</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;My Experience with Computers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2023-09-30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I am just getting started on this blog thing, I should talk about a little bit of history of me and computers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Windows XP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first time using a computer for real was on an old Windows XP workstation that was &lt;em&gt;liberated&lt;/em&gt; from a dumpster. It was (and still is, it is on my project shelf to become a pfSense router) an amazing little computer for what I did. I think I was about 7, and I only managed to break it a few times. I was trying so hard to find a way to edit videos on it to make Lego stop motions. The problem is there were not any free ones that were also low powered enough to run on that thing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The iMac&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When my parents saw my interest they surprised me and my siblings with an iMac. Granted, they also had work that required a powerful computer, but hey, I got my own account and was free to use it when not doing school or someone else was using it. From there, I used iMovie to create some really epic Lego stop motions. As I got older I started exploring things I may want to do... How I wanted to spend the rest of my life. That is when I decided to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@blenderguru&quot;&gt;learn&lt;/a&gt; 3D modeling in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blender.org/&quot;&gt;Blender&lt;/a&gt;. When I started to push the limits of the now aging iMac, I got my first job and decided it was time to buy my own computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Alienware R15&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can I start by saying don&#39;t buy an Alienware? There is just better ways to spend money. Anyway, I bought an Alienware R15 with a 8th gen Intel i7 and an Nvidia RTX 2060. At this point the main difference between macOS and Windows 10 was the &quot;X&quot; button moving, I was not that technical yet. The Alienware Laptop served me well as I worked on my 3D modeling skills. While 3D modeling, I discovered scripting with Python. I started to really enjoy making little Python scripts more than 3D modeling. After about a year of trying other things for short periods of time, I knew what I was made for. I am a software developer. I am naturally inclined to think like a computer and a touch of OCD helps me keep my code clean. After about 3 years with the Alienware, I had discovered Linux and I wanted to try it out. After raise at my job, the discovery of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@linustechtips&quot;&gt;LTT&lt;/a&gt;, and more general computing knowledge, it was time. I finally saved up and built my first desktop computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My First Build, &lt;em&gt;MidnightSlicer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first build went very well. I didn&#39;t have to take it apart again to get it to work like some do and it was overall an amazing experience (other than the whole MSI thing but I will write about that later). I built near the end of the crypto boom so I was only able to afford an RX 6600 XT, but it has been enough for what I do. The majority of my time on computers is spent doing CPU heavy work, with gaming being about a third priority. One interesting thing about this computer is I went out of my way to avoid RGB lights... Hence the name, MidnightSlicer. I installed Windows 11 on it for a little bit, but when I was finally ready to switch to Linux I installed Manjaro and have not went back to Windows since. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://mnsr.win/computers-and-me"/>
		<id>https://mnsr.win/computers-and-me</id>
		<updated>2023-09-30T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2023-09-30T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>Joining The 512KB Club</title>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Joining The 512KB Club&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2023-10-07&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a bit of a nerd for optimization. It is always satisfying to me when I am able to shave a fifth of a second off some operation or trivial task. I am the physical embodiment of spending 5 hours to save time on a 5 minute task. It is just so rewarding to me, even if some people don&#39;t get it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The 512KB Club?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://512kb.club/&quot;&gt;512KB Club&lt;/a&gt; is sort of like a webring for websites that are less than 512KB... obviously. On their home page they point out that many websites are now &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;several MB in size&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and bloated with JavaScript. There is almost no reason for a website to be that large. So, I decided to check mine... and it fits! My home page is about 15KB. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why Does This Matter?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, from a completely practical standpoint, smaller webpages result in faster loading times. If a webpage is large, people on poor internet connections or slower devices will struggle to load the page. In most cases, if a page takes too long to load people will just leave, which is sad if you want them to read your stuff. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you have a good internet connection and a simi-modern device, you will still see a notable hitch when loading large webpages. Just go to some bloated site, open the dev tools, go to the network section, and refresh the page to watch all those assets load in. It is wild. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the main reason for smaller webpages is &lt;em&gt;there is no good reason for them to be large&lt;/em&gt;. It is just a waste to create pretty visuals. I am constantly reminded of this when I have to visit a utility company&#39;s website. It is just stupid. They&#39;ve got fire, water, and lighting effects as a scroll down the page just trying to find the little &quot;pay my bills&quot; button. I don&#39;t want to see how much money you wasted on web design. I want to pay my bills and immediately leave. I guess the utility companies in my area got some government grant and they had to spend it somehow, so they made a &quot;pretty&quot; website. Beauty is in the eye of the beholder, and I behold JavaScript bloat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always bring it back to privacy. But really, if your website is smaller, it is harder to cram trackers in. It is certainly possible, but it is harder. It is also easier to review your website&#39;s code if there is less of it. I obviously believe you should have the freedom to visit a website without leaving a stain of your existence with details about your browser and browsing history (I&#39;m looking at you &lt;a href=&quot;https://brave.com/web-standards-at-brave/7-googles-topics-api/&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;). I know Nginx logs some information about the visitors of my website, but there are a few reasons that doesn&#39;t matter as much:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am not selling ads based off that information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am not selling that information to someone who would sell ads based off that information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;m not creepy 👁️&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I like small websites because they are more efficient. What am I going to do about these recent discoveries? obviously I am going to submit to join the 512KB Club! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: I am now a proud member of the green team of 512KB club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://512kb.club&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../public/badges/green-team.svg&quot; alt=&quot;a proud member of the green team of 512KB club&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
		<link href="https://mnsr.win/512KB"/>
		<id>https://mnsr.win/512KB</id>
		<updated>2023-10-07T10:00:00Z</updated>
		<published>2023-10-07T10:00:00Z</published>
	</entry>
</feed>
